Guide to the Larry Diamond Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Larry Diamond papers
1969-1977
SC0910
Diamond, Larry Jay
0.75 Linear feet
Collection includes memos, minutes, reports, correspondence, and background materials from Diamond’s work on the ASSU Task Force on Tenure and Teaching Quality (1976) and the Subcommittee on Female Admissions of the Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid (1971-72), of which he was the chairman. The charge to this committee was to assess the impact of admitting significantly more female students to Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical Sketch
Larry Diamond received all of his degrees from Stanford University: BA in 1974, an MA in 1978, and a PhD in sociology in 1980. He taught sociology at Vanderbilt University from 1980 to 1985 before returning to Stanford as a fellow at the Hoover Institution, where he is now a senior fellow as well as a professor of political science and sociology by courtesy.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes memos, minutes, reports, correspondence, and background materials from Diamond’s work on the ASSU Task Force on Tenure and Teaching Quality (1976) and the Subcommittee on Female Admissions of the Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid (1971-72), of which he was the chairman. The charge to this committee was to assess the impact of admitting significantly more female students to Stanford.
Access Terms
Associated Students of Stanford University. Task Force on Tenure and Teaching Quality.; Diamond, Larry Jay; Stanford University. Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid. Subcommittee on Female Admissions.; Coeducation.; College teachers--Tenure.; Universities and colleges--Faculty--Evaluation.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - ASSU Task Force on Tenure and Teaching Quality
    - Minutes, memos, notes, April-August 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Memos, notes, etc., Sept. 1976-January 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Working drafts of report, August-Dec. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Policy statements on tenure from SU schools, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Tenure information, 1969-76 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Teaching evaluation and improvement materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Teaching evaluation and improvement policies (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Appendix - evaluation forms, Princeton form, and letters (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Follow up to report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Background information (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1975 Survey of the American Professoriate, Everett Carll Ladd, Jr. and Seymour Martin Lipset, Nov. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Report of the Committee on the Professoriate at Stanford (incomplete), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Report of the ASSU Task Force on Tenure and Teaching Quality (as published in the Stanford Daily), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Subcommittee on Female Admissions (of the Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid)
    - Report, November 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Memos, drafts and notes, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, memos, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)